Guide to the Irwin Kremen Papers, 1992-2011 RL.11378
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Irwin Kremen papers
1992-2011
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kremen, Irwin
RL.11378
2.0 Linear Feet 1 box, 1 oversize folder
Exhibition annoucements, programs, and brochures for Irwin Kremen art exhibitions in the United States.
Biographical / Historical
Irwin Kremen (born 1925) is an American artist who at 41 began making art while Director of the Duke University Graduate Program in Clinical Psychology, after earning a Ph.D. six years earlier in clinical psychology at Harvard University.
Kremen's artwork mainly consists of non-representational collage, sculpture, and painting. In his later years he has defined a fourth grouping which he calls “multimodes."
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Irwin Kremen Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1995, 1997, 1999, 2002, 2012, 2017.
Collection Overview
Art exhibition flyers, bulletins, brochures, and programs from various Irwin Kremen shows, including C# (C Sharp) and The Re'eh Series.
Artists -- United States; Art -- 20th century -- Exhibitions; Artists -- North Carolina; Sculptors -- United States -- 20th century; Exhibition catalogs; Duke University -- Faculty
- North Carolina Literary Review (Vol. II, no. 2), 1995 (Box 1, Oversize-folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Black Mountain College issue with article and cover design by Kremen (signed, dated).
- Kremen lecture at Toyama College of Foreign Langauges: flyer, 1992 (Box 1)
- William Noland exhibit brochure, Raleigh, NC, 1995 (Box 1)
- Rolywholyover: A Circus: for museum by John Cage exhibition openings, invitations, 1994 (Box 1)
- John Cage: Scores from the Early 1950s exhibit brochure, program tribute, 1992, 1994 (Box 1)
- Black Mountain Connection exhibition, opening at Tampa Museum of Art, 1992 (Box 1)
- American Academy of Arts and Letters 44th purchase exhibition opening, 1992 (Box 1)
- Irwin Kremen: The Re'eh Series exhibition opening invitation, booklet, Archer M. Huntington Art Gallery, 1992 (Box 1)
- C#: Collage and Sculpture exhibition program and flyer, Green Hill Center for North Carolina Art, 1996 (Box 1, Oversize-folder 1)
- Metal Forms flyers, Durham Arts Guild, 1997 (Box 1)
- Seescape: Collages by Irwin Kremen programs, exhibition announcements, Mississippi Museum of Art, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
- Sam Ragan Fine Art Awards program, Laurinberg, N.C., 1998 (Box 1)
- As Such exhibition annoucements, Chicago Cultural Center, 2000 (Box 1)
- Three in One: Collage Painting Sculpture exhibition announcements, Nasher Museum of Art, 2004 (Box 1)
- In Site: Late Works by Irwin Kremen, Black Mountain College Museum and Arts Center, 2011 (Box 1)
- John Cage scores, 4' 33'', 1960, 1993 (Box 1)